<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-25T12:05:09+01:00</updated><id>https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/feed.xml</id><title type="html">PO2GO</title><subtitle>Jinpo's blog, about life, the universe and everything.
</subtitle><author><name>GitHub User</name></author><entry><title type="html">Climbing Mount Nantai</title><link href="https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/misc/2019/05/21/climbing-mount-nantai.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Climbing Mount Nantai" /><published>2019-05-21T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/misc/2019/05/21/climbing-mount-nantai</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/misc/2019/05/21/climbing-mount-nantai.html">&lt;p&gt;The last weekend of my stay in Japan, I wanted to visit somewhere memorable. Although the research project deadline loomed, it was worth cashing in on one last weekend trip. I had been scouting out worthwhile day trips from Tokyo, ideally a mountain to climb. Unfortunately we would miss the Mount Fuji climbing season (you can do it before June, but with ice axes, crampons, and bigger balls). Looking on the internet for places within a day trip of Tokyo, a few places came up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mount Nantai, near the Onsen resort town of Nikko, came up as the best option. One of Japan’s 100 famous mountains, it is an active volcano. Its name in Japanese literally translates as to “Man Body Mountain”. Standing at 2486 metres above sea level with a prominence of just over 1000m, Mount Nantai is an important religious site. The Holy Mountain providing the stream water, and therefore life, to the plains below where people lived. In fact the official start point of the hike is at a Shinto Shrine (Futarasan Shrine) by the shores of Lake Chuzenji where you pay the shrine attendants 500JPY for access to the path that ascends up the side of Mount Nantai. (Practical information at the end of the article).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left Tokyo early in the morning, around 07:45 in order to climb up and down again before dark. The Tobu-Nikko train departed from Tokyo Skytree station. We opted for the Spacia Express service as it was slightly faster and since we don’t have the JR RailPass it didn’t matter to us what train company we used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image full-par-width&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-paddies-200-231466.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-paddies-400-231466.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-paddies-800-231466.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-paddies-1600-231466.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-paddies-200-231466.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-paddies-400-231466.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-paddies-800-231466.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-paddies-1600-231466.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-paddies-800-231466.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beautiful Rice Paddies, on the way to Nikko&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Beautiful Rice Paddies, on the way to Nikko&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Nikko, and purchased the public transport pass at the train station. The whole day would have been easier if we had rented a car, but surprisingly the important destinations in the area were well served by buses. Japanese public transport is obviously always on time, so as long as you had a leaflet with the bus times printed on, you couldn’t really go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image almost-full-width&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-nantai-200-eb77c6.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-nantai-400-eb77c6.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-nantai-800-eb77c6.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-nantai-1600-eb77c6.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-nantai-200-eb77c6.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-nantai-400-eb77c6.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-nantai-800-eb77c6.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-nantai-1600-eb77c6.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-nantai-800-eb77c6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mount Nantai as seen from the car park near Kegon Waterfall. Note Sakura trees still blossoming.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Mount Nantai as seen from the car park near Kegon Waterfall. Note Sakura trees still blossoming.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to visit the Kegon Waterfall before we started our ascent of Mount Nantai, so we boarded the bus from Tobu-Nikko station, the journey would last approximately 50 minutes. Kegon Waterfall is a fairly well known (maybe infamous?) spot in the Nikko area. The main waterfall drops almost 100 metres, and a cluster of smaller waterfalls are dispersed to the side and behind the main waterfall, with water gushing through cracks in the volcanic rock. Kegon Waterfall is known as a popular suicide spot especially for Japanese youths, I am unsure why this is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The waterfall is about 5 minutes from a bus stop and a further 25 minute walk along the main road next to Lake Chuzenji brings you to the Shrine, where you access the mountain trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image portrait-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-waterfall-200-5a6326.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-waterfall-400-5a6326.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-waterfall-800-5a6326.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-waterfall-1600-5a6326.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-waterfall-200-5a6326.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-waterfall-400-5a6326.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-waterfall-800-5a6326.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-waterfall-1600-5a6326.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-waterfall-800-5a6326.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking down to Lake Chuzenji&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Looking down to Lake Chuzenji&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The waterfall can be seen from a platform near the road. For an extra experience, you can purchase tickets to take a ride down an elevator which takes you down to the bottom of the waterfall… we did this but I would say save your yen and just admire it from the top. It didn’t help that there was a large school group in front of us so waiting for the elevator took a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we came up the elevator, we headed towards the start of the trail. Shops along the road sold food and inflatable toys for swimming in the lake. If we had more time, we would have definitely explored the lake a little more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;image half-par left&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-sunout-200-02e876.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-sunout-400-02e876.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-sunout-800-02e876.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-sunout-1600-02e876.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-sunout-200-02e876.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-sunout-400-02e876.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-sunout-800-02e876.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-sunout-1600-02e876.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-sunout-800-02e876.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Suns out, Guns out. Through the forest at the beginning of the trail.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Suns out, Guns out. Through the forest at the beginning of the trail.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;figure class=&quot;image half-par right&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-looking-down-200-3e3eb4.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-looking-down-400-3e3eb4.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-looking-down-800-3e3eb4.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-looking-down-1600-3e3eb4.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-looking-down-200-3e3eb4.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-looking-down-400-3e3eb4.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-looking-down-800-3e3eb4.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-looking-down-1600-3e3eb4.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-05-21-climbing-mount-nantai-looking-down-800-3e3eb4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Suns out, Guns out. Through the forest at the beginning of the trail.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Suns out, Guns out. Through the forest at the beginning of the trail.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Futarasan Shrine itself is not particularly remarkable. Tori gates line the entrance to the shrine. The general atmosphere is very peaceful, there probably are not as many visitors to this shrine as there are to the main ones closer to Nikko. An attendant in a kiosk takes 500JPY from you and provides you with a small map roughly showing you the way up, and a small shinto charm, (apparently providing good luck for travellers and those that make journeys, according to a colleague of mine).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>GitHub User</name></author><summary type="html">The last weekend of my stay in Japan, I wanted to visit somewhere memorable. Although the research project deadline loomed, it was worth cashing in on one last weekend trip. I had been scouting out worthwhile day trips from Tokyo, ideally a mountain to climb. Unfortunately we would miss the Mount Fuji climbing season (you can do it before June, but with ice axes, crampons, and bigger balls). Looking on the internet for places within a day trip of Tokyo, a few places came up. Mount Nantai, near the Onsen resort town of Nikko, came up as the best option. One of Japan’s 100 famous mountains, it is an active volcano. Its name in Japanese literally translates as to “Man Body Mountain”. Standing at 2486 metres above sea level with a prominence of just over 1000m, Mount Nantai is an important religious site. The Holy Mountain providing the stream water, and therefore life, to the plains below where people lived. In fact the official start point of the hike is at a Shinto Shrine (Futarasan Shrine) by the shores of Lake Chuzenji where you pay the shrine attendants 500JPY for access to the path that ascends up the side of Mount Nantai. (Practical information at the end of the article). We left Tokyo early in the morning, around 07:45 in order to climb up and down again before dark. The Tobu-Nikko train departed from Tokyo Skytree station. We opted for the Spacia Express service as it was slightly faster and since we don’t have the JR RailPass it didn’t matter to us what train company we used. Beautiful Rice Paddies, on the way to Nikko We arrived in Nikko, and purchased the public transport pass at the train station. The whole day would have been easier if we had rented a car, but surprisingly the important destinations in the area were well served by buses. Japanese public transport is obviously always on time, so as long as you had a leaflet with the bus times printed on, you couldn’t really go wrong. Mount Nantai as seen from the car park near Kegon Waterfall. Note Sakura trees still blossoming. We decided to visit the Kegon Waterfall before we started our ascent of Mount Nantai, so we boarded the bus from Tobu-Nikko station, the journey would last approximately 50 minutes. Kegon Waterfall is a fairly well known (maybe infamous?) spot in the Nikko area. The main waterfall drops almost 100 metres, and a cluster of smaller waterfalls are dispersed to the side and behind the main waterfall, with water gushing through cracks in the volcanic rock. Kegon Waterfall is known as a popular suicide spot especially for Japanese youths, I am unsure why this is. The waterfall is about 5 minutes from a bus stop and a further 25 minute walk along the main road next to Lake Chuzenji brings you to the Shrine, where you access the mountain trail. Looking down to Lake Chuzenji The waterfall can be seen from a platform near the road. For an extra experience, you can purchase tickets to take a ride down an elevator which takes you down to the bottom of the waterfall… we did this but I would say save your yen and just admire it from the top. It didn’t help that there was a large school group in front of us so waiting for the elevator took a while. After we came up the elevator, we headed towards the start of the trail. Shops along the road sold food and inflatable toys for swimming in the lake. If we had more time, we would have definitely explored the lake a little more. Suns out, Guns out. Through the forest at the beginning of the trail. Suns out, Guns out. Through the forest at the beginning of the trail. Futarasan Shrine itself is not particularly remarkable. Tori gates line the entrance to the shrine. The general atmosphere is very peaceful, there probably are not as many visitors to this shrine as there are to the main ones closer to Nikko. An attendant in a kiosk takes 500JPY from you and provides you with a small map roughly showing you the way up, and a small shinto charm, (apparently providing good luck for travellers and those that make journeys, according to a colleague of mine).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ODAIBA AND TEAMLAB BORDERLESS (HONEST REVIEW)</title><link href="https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/misc/2019/03/10/odaiba-teamlab-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ODAIBA AND TEAMLAB BORDERLESS (HONEST REVIEW)" /><published>2019-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/misc/2019/03/10/odaiba-teamlab-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/misc/2019/03/10/odaiba-teamlab-review.html"></content><author><name>GitHub User</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AN AFTERNOON ALONG THE EDOGAWA RIVER</title><link href="https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/misc/2019/03/02/edogawa-river.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AN AFTERNOON ALONG THE EDOGAWA RIVER" /><published>2019-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/misc/2019/03/02/edogawa-river</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/misc/2019/03/02/edogawa-river.html">&lt;p&gt;A few days after moving to Japan and Ichikawa City, I felt the urge to explore the local neighbourhood. I had already seen enough of Konodai Campus, explored every aisle of the FamilyMart next to campus and in fact signed up for the FamilyMart Loyalty Card since the famichiki had a small discount if you were a member of the Loyalty Scheme. Having felt I’d seen enough of my immediate surroundings. on the first Saturday of my stay in Japan, I decided to go for a walk. Google Maps suggested the local park was fairly nice, with a few rave reviews of the rose garden. Not expecting much, I walked out of our accommodation compound and across the road into Satomi Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satomi Park during weekdays is relatively quiet, with the occasional retiree taking their daily walk through the gently manicured hedges and trees. However, at the weekend, the atmosphere light up, with parents taking their children out to play on their days off, nature lovers armed with cannon length canon cameras pointing up into the tree branches waiting for birds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image full-par-width&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-camera-200-ed8a45.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-camera-400-ed8a45.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-camera-800-ed8a45.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-camera-1600-ed8a45.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-camera-200-ed8a45.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-camera-400-ed8a45.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-camera-800-ed8a45.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-camera-1600-ed8a45.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-camera-800-ed8a45.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bird Watchers in the park.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Bird Watchers in the park.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image full-par-width&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-park-200-d47769.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-park-400-d47769.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-park-800-d47769.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-park-1600-d47769.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-park-200-d47769.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-park-400-d47769.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-park-800-d47769.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-park-1600-d47769.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-park-800-d47769.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Satomi Park.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Satomi Park.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image full-par-width&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-fountain-200-0057be.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-fountain-400-0057be.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-fountain-800-0057be.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-fountain-1600-0057be.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-fountain-200-0057be.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-fountain-400-0057be.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-fountain-800-0057be.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-fountain-1600-0057be.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-fountain-800-0057be.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Early Sakura in Satomi Park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Early Sakura in Satomi Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People of all ages, all walks of life, liberated by the weekend came out in droves to the park and surrounding area on their days off. Some exercised, some played, some pursued their hobbies, others walked their dogs. It was incredibly warming to see this outburst of human energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left Satomi Park and made my way towards the Edogawa River via steep stone steps leading down from the Park. It was here, framed by the trees of Satomi Park, was the Tokyo Metropolis sprawled in the hazy distance, the Tokyo Sky Tree dominating the skyline of the man made concrete forest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image full-width&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-river-200-a6cf16.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-river-400-a6cf16.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-river-800-a6cf16.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-river-1600-a6cf16.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-river-200-a6cf16.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-river-400-a6cf16.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-river-800-a6cf16.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-river-1600-a6cf16.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-river-800-a6cf16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The View across the Edogawa River towards the Tokyo Metropolis. On the left is the outline of the Tokyo Skytree, and towards the centre is the main business district of Shinjuku. Next to the river is the raised embankment which acts as a flood defence during natural disasters.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;The View across the Edogawa River towards the Tokyo Metropolis. On the left is the outline of the Tokyo Skytree, and towards the centre is the main business district of Shinjuku. Next to the river is the raised embankment which acts as a flood defence during natural disasters.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Edogawa River forms the border between Tokyo and Chiba Prefecture. The river empties out into the Bay of Tokyo, near the Tokyo DisneySea Resort. What’s really interesting is the way that the river has been adapted to act as a Tsunami defence, with flood gates periodically installed along the banks of the river. A large water drainage system that operates in cavernous tunnels under Tokyo City eventually drain out into the Edogawa River. In the above photo you can see a raised grassy bank running alongside the river bank. This is a Tsunami defence wall but with a wide tarmac path running along the top, also doubles up as a leisure space for local residents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image full-par-width&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-playing-200-2c9792.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-playing-400-2c9792.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-playing-800-2c9792.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-playing-1600-2c9792.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-playing-200-2c9792.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-playing-400-2c9792.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-playing-800-2c9792.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-playing-1600-2c9792.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-playing-800-2c9792.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view along the embankment, the grassy areas between it and the river have been turned into playing fields.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;A view along the embankment, the grassy areas between it and the river have been turned into playing fields.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image full-par-width&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-rcplane-200-6f1ab6.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-rcplane-400-6f1ab6.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-rcplane-800-6f1ab6.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-rcplane-1600-6f1ab6.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-rcplane-200-6f1ab6.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-rcplane-400-6f1ab6.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-rcplane-800-6f1ab6.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-rcplane-1600-6f1ab6.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-rcplane-800-6f1ab6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A group of remote control plane enthusiasts watch on as their friends race by the river.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;A group of remote control plane enthusiasts watch on as their friends race by the river.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A walk along the raised embankment reveals much about ordinary life in Japan and for me personally was a calming experience as I slowly acclimatised to my new temporary home. There was a sense of familiarity seeing the kids playing football and baseball by the river, a small group of men pulling little trailers stacked with radio controlled airplanes and helicopters had set up a little race track next to the river and were racing one another. This normality and community spirit was very relaxing to see, and opposite to the weekday work atmosphere of hurried men and women in business suits walking with stride and purpose to their engagements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;image half-par left&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-farmland-200-b80a73.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-farmland-400-b80a73.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-farmland-800-b80a73.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-farmland-1600-b80a73.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-farmland-200-b80a73.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-farmland-400-b80a73.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-farmland-800-b80a73.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-farmland-1600-b80a73.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-farmland-800-b80a73.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A small patch of farmland by the river.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;A small patch of farmland by the river.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;figure class=&quot;image half-par right&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sweat-200-cdc91c.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sweat-400-cdc91c.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sweat-800-cdc91c.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sweat-1600-cdc91c.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sweat-200-cdc91c.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sweat-400-cdc91c.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sweat-800-cdc91c.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sweat-1600-cdc91c.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sweat-800-cdc91c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pocari Sweat – Probably unique to Japan, a replenishment drink that tastes like flat Sprite with enough ion balance to resuscitate a dehydrated elephant. 1 litre of Pocari Cures any Hangover.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Pocari Sweat – Probably unique to Japan, a replenishment drink that tastes like flat Sprite with enough ion balance to resuscitate a dehydrated elephant. 1 litre of Pocari Cures any Hangover.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 2 miles further north from Satomi Park along the Edogawa River, the buildings thinned out, and patches of farmland appear. It was a surprise to see agriculture so close to the city. A small shop by the side of the road sold produce and documented the use of this land over the last century as an important supply of food for the local population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A slow saunter back to Konodai Campus late in the afternoon followed, the activities along the river continued, a small boat with a wake boarder went up and down the straight part of the river as the Sunlight eventually faded out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image full-width&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sunsetpan-200-44039f.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sunsetpan-400-44039f.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sunsetpan-800-44039f.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sunsetpan-1600-44039f.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sunsetpan-200-44039f.jpg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sunsetpan-400-44039f.jpg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sunsetpan-800-44039f.jpg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sunsetpan-1600-44039f.jpg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-03-02-edogawa-river-sunsetpan-800-44039f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset over the river.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sunset over the river.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set out to walk through Satomi Park and along the river next to the dormitory just to explore the local area, but this turned out to be more than a google maps navigation exercise. I was somewhat apprehensive about the start of my stay in Japan. I was to live in a relatively poorly lit room which was quite cold at night, and had a musty smell like a damp attic. Apples were almost 4 times the cost in England, and the prospect of a Nandos Fino Wrap was distant at best. But this walk along the river normalised many elements of life in Japan. Seeing people outside of the weekday work environment, relaxing and being able to enjoy their time off with family and friends, partaking in hobbies and sports, made me feel more settled. Knowing that underneath the tough work ethic and ridiculously long working days, there was still life and joy to be had.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>GitHub User</name></author><summary type="html">A few days after moving to Japan and Ichikawa City, I felt the urge to explore the local neighbourhood. I had already seen enough of Konodai Campus, explored every aisle of the FamilyMart next to campus and in fact signed up for the FamilyMart Loyalty Card since the famichiki had a small discount if you were a member of the Loyalty Scheme. Having felt I’d seen enough of my immediate surroundings. on the first Saturday of my stay in Japan, I decided to go for a walk. Google Maps suggested the local park was fairly nice, with a few rave reviews of the rose garden. Not expecting much, I walked out of our accommodation compound and across the road into Satomi Park. Satomi Park during weekdays is relatively quiet, with the occasional retiree taking their daily walk through the gently manicured hedges and trees. However, at the weekend, the atmosphere light up, with parents taking their children out to play on their days off, nature lovers armed with cannon length canon cameras pointing up into the tree branches waiting for birds. Bird Watchers in the park. Satomi Park. Early Sakura in Satomi Park People of all ages, all walks of life, liberated by the weekend came out in droves to the park and surrounding area on their days off. Some exercised, some played, some pursued their hobbies, others walked their dogs. It was incredibly warming to see this outburst of human energy. I left Satomi Park and made my way towards the Edogawa River via steep stone steps leading down from the Park. It was here, framed by the trees of Satomi Park, was the Tokyo Metropolis sprawled in the hazy distance, the Tokyo Sky Tree dominating the skyline of the man made concrete forest. The View across the Edogawa River towards the Tokyo Metropolis. On the left is the outline of the Tokyo Skytree, and towards the centre is the main business district of Shinjuku. Next to the river is the raised embankment which acts as a flood defence during natural disasters. The Edogawa River forms the border between Tokyo and Chiba Prefecture. The river empties out into the Bay of Tokyo, near the Tokyo DisneySea Resort. What’s really interesting is the way that the river has been adapted to act as a Tsunami defence, with flood gates periodically installed along the banks of the river. A large water drainage system that operates in cavernous tunnels under Tokyo City eventually drain out into the Edogawa River. In the above photo you can see a raised grassy bank running alongside the river bank. This is a Tsunami defence wall but with a wide tarmac path running along the top, also doubles up as a leisure space for local residents. A view along the embankment, the grassy areas between it and the river have been turned into playing fields. A group of remote control plane enthusiasts watch on as their friends race by the river. A walk along the raised embankment reveals much about ordinary life in Japan and for me personally was a calming experience as I slowly acclimatised to my new temporary home. There was a sense of familiarity seeing the kids playing football and baseball by the river, a small group of men pulling little trailers stacked with radio controlled airplanes and helicopters had set up a little race track next to the river and were racing one another. This normality and community spirit was very relaxing to see, and opposite to the weekday work atmosphere of hurried men and women in business suits walking with stride and purpose to their engagements. A small patch of farmland by the river. Pocari Sweat – Probably unique to Japan, a replenishment drink that tastes like flat Sprite with enough ion balance to resuscitate a dehydrated elephant. 1 litre of Pocari Cures any Hangover. About 2 miles further north from Satomi Park along the Edogawa River, the buildings thinned out, and patches of farmland appear. It was a surprise to see agriculture so close to the city. A small shop by the side of the road sold produce and documented the use of this land over the last century as an important supply of food for the local population. A slow saunter back to Konodai Campus late in the afternoon followed, the activities along the river continued, a small boat with a wake boarder went up and down the straight part of the river as the Sunlight eventually faded out. Sunset over the river. I set out to walk through Satomi Park and along the river next to the dormitory just to explore the local area, but this turned out to be more than a google maps navigation exercise. I was somewhat apprehensive about the start of my stay in Japan. I was to live in a relatively poorly lit room which was quite cold at night, and had a musty smell like a damp attic. Apples were almost 4 times the cost in England, and the prospect of a Nandos Fino Wrap was distant at best. But this walk along the river normalised many elements of life in Japan. Seeing people outside of the weekday work environment, relaxing and being able to enjoy their time off with family and friends, partaking in hobbies and sports, made me feel more settled. Knowing that underneath the tough work ethic and ridiculously long working days, there was still life and joy to be had.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">THE JAPANESE ADVENTURE BEGINS!</title><link href="https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/misc/2019/02/26/japanese-adventure-begins.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="THE JAPANESE ADVENTURE BEGINS!" /><published>2019-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/misc/2019/02/26/japanese-adventure-begins</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cadamswaite.github.io/po2go//po2go/misc/2019/02/26/japanese-adventure-begins.html">&lt;p&gt;Konichiwa folks! I will be living in Japan from the end of February until May 2019 to do a research project at a University Hospital in Tokyo. I will be posting about life in Japan, places that I have travelled to, and possibly niche content on the pathology based research I am doing. Some posts will be massively retrospective as towards the end of my stay, the workload got pretty hectic and I didn’t have time to write as much as I would like, but I will try and do things in a chronological order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tokyo, the capital city of Japan, is arguably the most populated metropolis in the world. What really hit me upon arrival was just how dense the buildings, both commercial and residential, were laid out in the city but unlike other major cities where you tend to find a concentrated centre which thins out in terms of building and population density. Tokyo seemingly maintains this intense density of housing and people for miles and miles out of the centre of the City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Accommodation was quite far outside of Tokyo. Far enough in fact that technically we were in Chiba Prefecture. Yet, as you took the Chuo Sobu Commuter train from the centre of town to our local station of Ichikawa, there was no feeling that you had left the City, Narrow streets draped with neon signs and telephone poles seem to repetitively swing past the train window as you left Tokyo City and crossed the Edogawa River to Ichikawa. For the duration of our stay, I would be living in University Accommodation near Ichikawa in a district called Konodai, along with the four other exchange students. All of us were doing research projects at a central Hospital as part of our undergraduate studies and we were living in a dormitory with other international exchange students from across all continents also conducting medical research in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Settling in took longer than expected. We arrived at the end of February, London temperatures were still fairly mild when we left. The climate in Tokyo seems to be very cold winters, very hot summers and a mild in between period which luckily we would be able to experience. Our accommodation was not what we were used to, the spaces were small, the astronauts onboard the ISS probably have a bigger kitchen area and more hobs.. We had a single bed, and a large desk filling one side of the room and a air conditioning unit which doubled up as the heater for the room for the colder winter months. A small balcony outside provided a space to hang up washing, but also a habitat for some 6 -8 legged friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;image half-par left&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-exterior-200-02b58e.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-exterior-400-02b58e.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-exterior-800-02b58e.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-exterior-1600-02b58e.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-exterior-200-02b58e.jpeg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-exterior-400-02b58e.jpeg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-exterior-800-02b58e.jpeg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-exterior-1600-02b58e.jpeg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-exterior-800-02b58e.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The Exterior of our Accommodation, pastel colours on well fortified concrete bastions.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Exterior of our Accommodation, pastel colours on well fortified concrete bastions.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;figure class=&quot;image half-par right&quot;&gt;
  &lt;picture class=&quot;awesome&quot; data-volume=&quot;11&quot;&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-bed-200-756606.webp 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-bed-400-756606.webp 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-bed-800-756606.webp 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-bed-1600-756606.webp 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;source sizes=&quot;(max-width: 600px) 100vw, (max-width: 1800px) 60vw, 800px&quot; srcset=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-bed-200-756606.jpeg 200w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-bed-400-756606.jpeg 400w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-bed-800-756606.jpeg 800w, /po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-bed-1600-756606.jpeg 1600w&quot; type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;some-other-class&quot; src=&quot;/po2go/generated/img/2019-02-26-japanese-adventure-begins-bed-800-756606.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;First day in the new home, featuring Floppsy the toy rabbit.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;First day in the new home, featuring Floppsy the toy rabbit.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The international dormitory had an exterior appearance reminiscent of a minimum security detention centre, with barren concrete walls, rusting metal rails and some sort of watch tower painted a garish pastel pink to liften the spirits of the research inmates housed inside.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>GitHub User</name></author><summary type="html">Konichiwa folks! I will be living in Japan from the end of February until May 2019 to do a research project at a University Hospital in Tokyo. I will be posting about life in Japan, places that I have travelled to, and possibly niche content on the pathology based research I am doing. Some posts will be massively retrospective as towards the end of my stay, the workload got pretty hectic and I didn’t have time to write as much as I would like, but I will try and do things in a chronological order. Tokyo, the capital city of Japan, is arguably the most populated metropolis in the world. What really hit me upon arrival was just how dense the buildings, both commercial and residential, were laid out in the city but unlike other major cities where you tend to find a concentrated centre which thins out in terms of building and population density. Tokyo seemingly maintains this intense density of housing and people for miles and miles out of the centre of the City. Our Accommodation was quite far outside of Tokyo. Far enough in fact that technically we were in Chiba Prefecture. Yet, as you took the Chuo Sobu Commuter train from the centre of town to our local station of Ichikawa, there was no feeling that you had left the City, Narrow streets draped with neon signs and telephone poles seem to repetitively swing past the train window as you left Tokyo City and crossed the Edogawa River to Ichikawa. For the duration of our stay, I would be living in University Accommodation near Ichikawa in a district called Konodai, along with the four other exchange students. All of us were doing research projects at a central Hospital as part of our undergraduate studies and we were living in a dormitory with other international exchange students from across all continents also conducting medical research in Japan. Settling in took longer than expected. We arrived at the end of February, London temperatures were still fairly mild when we left. The climate in Tokyo seems to be very cold winters, very hot summers and a mild in between period which luckily we would be able to experience. Our accommodation was not what we were used to, the spaces were small, the astronauts onboard the ISS probably have a bigger kitchen area and more hobs.. We had a single bed, and a large desk filling one side of the room and a air conditioning unit which doubled up as the heater for the room for the colder winter months. A small balcony outside provided a space to hang up washing, but also a habitat for some 6 -8 legged friends. The Exterior of our Accommodation, pastel colours on well fortified concrete bastions. First day in the new home, featuring Floppsy the toy rabbit. The international dormitory had an exterior appearance reminiscent of a minimum security detention centre, with barren concrete walls, rusting metal rails and some sort of watch tower painted a garish pastel pink to liften the spirits of the research inmates housed inside.</summary></entry></feed>